how do you know whether you can use
something from the HTML from HTML or css
or
JavaScript um we've done videos in the
past uh and I I'll do another video
about things like Mozilla or free code
camp or W3 fools there's another video I
have about going rtfm going to the
specification that's the best place to
go for any learning regarding HTML
because that is literally the
specification but somebody raised the
valid question um B how do I know that
something in the specification has been
actually implemented number one uh since
the creation of what WG the working
group that this is primarily maintained
by the biggest browser manufacturers on
the planet including Mozilla um Firefox
and so you know you already have a
pretty good idea uh that the standard
that's being maintain the living
standard that's being maintained and I
talk about that in the other video but
there Still Remains the question which
browser allows me to use what and this
is a big topic um it's not a part of the
beginner boost though and that I wasn't
going to do a video about this because
it's extra this does not apply to the
basic stuff that we do for static web
documentation web documents you know
website development this the stuff that
we're going to cover in the beginner
boost you never ever need need to use
this site for this but because somebody
raised a question I'm going to go ahead
and mention it now in an extra video um
so if you take a look here this is it
it's a site called caniuse.com This is
hands down the definitive Authority
about what technologies can be used and
whether you want to use a thing and and
by the way this is important I thank God
you didn't live through the 9s that
raise your hand if you live through the
browser Wars of the 90s where One
browser manufacturer would would do
something deliberately that was not
compatible with somebody else and then
they they kept fighting with each other
to try to get people to buy into their
idea and then people would make websites
for it uh it was around that time that
um that there God I can't even remember
the name of it now um I can see his name
I can see his face in my head there
there were a lot of technologies that
that evolved to help uh bridge that Gap
so that people so developers could
actually make you know websites with
JavaScript and different thing um I
can't remember the name of it now the
name it's so it's been so long it's long
ago um anyway so so that was um a a time
and and but that that day is is largely
passed even Microsoft Edge uh contains
Chrome at chromium at this point all
major web browsers except for Apple um
are using the same basic web engines so
thankfully you usually don't have to
come out to can I use very often uh but
what would you come out here to find so
one of my favorite Technologies is
flexbox and now I know this is not
something we're going to learnning the
Boost but flexbox is uh some a
technology that emerged for laying out
components um on the screen in a way
that's much more flexible
than you know things like tables and
stuff that we used in the 90s um again
this is not a web development Topic in
terms of like you know for the beginner
boost but I wanted to mention this um
those of you who don't know about it
it's a great way to know where to go to
see whether it's been supported another
another technology if you want to do any
kind of game development um is you might
want to check and see if websockets is
supported well what version is it
supported in right um and these you know
this gives you extremely exhaustive uh
breakdown of every single Nuance um and
it actually does link to uh other
documentation sources including mdn um
that another person mentioned that
Microsoft developer or mazilla developer
network is the place to go to um this
this is actually a good resource it I'll
do a separate video on it it
unfortunately has errors quite
frequently um so I do recommend you go
to the specification first
and the second the the second resource I
would go to would be can I use because
this is going to tell you very
definitively uh what exact version
you're going to adopt and and whether
you can use it without getting into
trouble uh we've had people deploy
things uh to the Enterprise that were
not supported by the standard Enterprise
browser and they could have avoided that
had they gone to can I use to check in
advance for that kind of thing um and
again this this does implement the M the
Milla developer network and on top of uh
the can I use uh thing so so if if
something's going to be found or it's
got an issue this is where it's going to
show up first